anitab.org 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - AnitaB.org

Last Updated: June 21, 2018

Your privacy is important, so the Anita Borg Institute for Women and Technology (“AnitaB.org”) has created the following Privacy Policy to let you know what information we collect when you visit our Site(s) (as defined below), use our online services, or otherwise engage with us, and why we collect this information and how it is used.

## **Your Consent To This Privacy Policy**

By using the Site(s), you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not want information about you to be used in the manner set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site(s).

This is our entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into by reference and made a part of our Terms of Use for the Sites. We may periodically make changes to this Privacy Policy that we will include on this page. The effective date at the top of this page indicates the date of the most current Privacy Policy in effect. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy frequently and remain informed about any changes to it, so we encourage you to visit this page often. Your continued use of the Site(s) constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions. AnitaB.org shall not be liable for any damages You may suffer as a result of its failure to provide you notice of any changes to this Privacy Policy as set forth herein. If you would like to be notified when this Privacy Policy is updated, please contact us by email at [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org) or by postal mail at Privacy Director, Anita Borg Institute for Women and Technology, 1501 Page Mill Road, MS 1105, Palo Alto, CA 94304.

## **Scope of Policy**

This Privacy Policy explains the data collection and use practices of anitaborg.org, anitab.org, systers.org and any other websites or services, available through such sites, owned or operated by AnitaB.org (each a “Site” and, collectively, the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party sites with which AnitaB.org may be affiliated. Please consult the privacy policies of such third-party sites. Certain additional terms governing privacy on the Systers.org site (“Systers Site”) and restricted-access e-mail discussion lists, now or in the future (the “Systers Lists”) are set forth on the [Systers List FAQs](http://wiki.systers.org/communities/doku.php/wiki/systers/faq) and below. AnitaB.org only provides information to third-parties that is necessary to successfully achieve the purpose for which the information was collected.

## **Your Rights**

AnitaB.org is committed to honoring your privacy rights as follows:

  * Right of access to your personal information
  * Right to rectification of personal information help where it is incorrect or incomplete
  * Right of erasure of personal information (the “right to be forgotten”) if certain grounds are met
  * Right to restrict or suspend the processing of personal information
  * Right to complain to a supervisory authority should you believe your personal information is being misused
  * Right of data portability (if processing is based on consent and automated means)
  * Right to withdraw consent at any time (if processing is based on consent)
  * Right to object to processing (if processing is based on legitimate interests)
  * Right to object to processing of personal information for direct marketing purposes

## **What Information Is Collected?**

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including an individual’s first and last name, password, home or other physical address, an email address, phone number or other contact information.

You may provide personal information to AnitaB.org in connection with making a donation to AnitaB.org. We call personal information directly associated with donations “Donor Information.” Except with your explicit permission, we will not sell, share or trade Donor Information with any third party, nor send mailings using Donor information on behalf of other organizations. To the extent any Donor Information is processed through a third-party service provider, Donor Information will only be used for purposes necessary to process that activity.

Depending on how you initiate contact with AnitaB.org, we may ask you for any of the following information:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Country of residence
  * Date of birth
  * Company affiliation
  * Career level
  * Information typically included on a resume
  * Payment processing information such as credit card number, postal code, and bank account information
  * Gender
  * Mailing address
  * Phone number
  * Age
  * Organization/Company
  * Professional Title
  * Professional Affiliation
  * Education
  * Racial Identity
  * Food Allergies
  * Special Accomodations

Generally, the information you provide when interacting with AnitaB.org is optional, but some information may be required in order for a particular process, transaction, or other interaction to properly execute. AnitaB.org may be unable to provide you with certain products or services should you elect not to share information that we require to be collected for a particular purpose. If you have questions about what information we will require to be collected for a particular purpose, please contact us at [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org).

AnitaB.org also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, information contained in or conveyed by cookies and other similar technology (as described below), and the page you request through automated a metrics platform such as Google Analytics. This information is automatically logged through these services and will not be connected to your personal information by AnitaB.org for any reason.

AnitaB.org may also collect certain personal information or other information that you voluntarily disclosed, including without limitation in connection with registering for events or mailing lists, submission of job applications, responses to survey questions, providing comments, suggestions, and other information that you voluntarily submit. If you choose to provide such information, you are giving AnitaB.org the permission to use and store it consistent with this policy. Therefore, please understand that when you sign in with AnitaB.org, you are not anonymous to us.

We may also obtain information, including personal information, from third parties and other sources. If we combine or associate information from other sources with personal information that we collect, we will treat the combined information as personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## **How Is Such Information Used?**

We may use personal information we collect in order to establish and enhance our relationship with you. AnitaB.org may use personal information to share with you information that we feel may be of interest to you, such as invitations to attend AnitaB.org events or the events of other carefully chosen organizations, to review and enhance our products and service offerings, to contact you about your membership, to provide local networking and educational opportunities, or otherwise to further our charitable purpose and to comply with applicable law. If you make charitable donations to AnitaB.org or otherwise engage in off-line activities with AnitaB.org, this Donor Information may be merged in our database with your online personal information. The information AnitaB.org collects and how the information is used will specifically depend on which of AnitaB.org’s products or services you use. AnitaB.org will only require you to provide us with information if it is needed for the legitimate interest of providing you with a product or service or the execution of a transaction. Any time you voluntarily submit information in additional to that described above, you are providing the information on a voluntary basis whereby you consent to our use of the information as described at the time requested. You can contact us at any time to adjust your privacy preferences or ask questions about how the information might be used.

Your personal information is only retained by AnitaB.org for as long as needed to facilitate the product or service, facilitate communication, or otherwise execute the purpose for which the information was obtained in the first place. This means that although much of the information can be deleted automatically (e.g. when you elect to unsubscribe from a newsletter), some will require manual review before doing so (e.g. you have purchased a ticket for an event and we need some way to verify who you are in order to be admitted to the event).

Tasks related to event organization and other functions of AnitaB.org are performed both by employees, agents and contractors of AnitaB.org and by volunteers (“AnitaB.org Volunteers”) who are not employees. By making use of the Site(s), you consent to allow AnitaB.org employees, agents, contractors, and AnitaB.org Volunteers to access any personal information you submit to the Site(s) to provide AnitaB.org with a specific service and not for any other purpose.

Additionally, AnitaB.org generally uses the information to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the Site(s). Under certain circumstances (for example if you win a contest) we may post your personal information on the Site(s). However, we will notify you of this possibility when collecting personal information or we will obtain your consent to post this information. We may share your personal information with certain other websites that we link to (and that you click upon) in order to achieve the purpose of the connection with the Site(s). AnitaB.org may also use the information that we collect to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users, to improve the way the Site(s) work and look, and to create new features and functionality. The information may be stored and maintained for as long as reasonably necessary to effectuate the service requested and for a reasonable time thereafter.

## **When AnitaB.org Discloses Information**

AnitaB.org discloses information to third parties as follows: (i) to agents, subcontractors and other third parties, including AnitaB.org volunteers, who are engaged by AnitaB.org in making the AnitaB.org products and services available and otherwise assisting AnitaB.org in its charitable purpose, including fundraising; and (ii) to selected affiliates, marketing partners and other organizations that AnitaB.org may affiliate with in furtherance of its charitable purpose. In addition, if you register to attend an event or conference sponsored by AnitaB.org, AnitaB.org may also disclose a list of attendee contact information to other attendees at such conference or event; provided, that AnitaB.org will provide attendees with the opportunity to opt-out of such disclosure. As described above, to the extent any Donor Information is processed through a third-party service provider, Donor Information will only be used for purposes necessary to process that activity.

AnitaB.org may disclose information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) comply with state or federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright law), or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant, or otherwise comply with legal process served on AnitaB.org or the Site(s); (2) protect and defend the rights or property of AnitaB.org or otherwise take precautions against liability; or (3) act in urgent circumstances to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of AnitaB.org and users of AnitaB.org, its websites or the public; (4) protect AnitaB.org from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses;(5) investigate and defend ourselves against third party claims or allegations; (6) assist government enforcement agencies; or (7) protect the security or integrity of the Site(s).

## **Systers Site**

AnitaB.org collects the following personal information from you when you register to use the Systers List: e-mail address, full name, gender, and a short essay discussing involvement in technical computing. We also collect and archive submissions to the Systers List and thus we retain any personal information you choose to include in those submissions. This site is a conversation-style site where members post questions and answers to each other and engage in other forms of communication based on the interests of the collective group. The information AnitaB.org collects from the members of the site is only for the purpose of ensuring the security and privacy

Personal information collected on the Systers Site may be used for the purposes of enabling registration, maintenance, support and participation in the Systers List.

In addition, archives of emails sent to the Systers List are maintained on the Systers Site and are accessible to list members. When they register to participate, Systers List members agree to be bound by the [Systers List FAQs](http://wiki.systers.org/communities/doku.php/wiki/systers/faq), which requires that information posted to the Systers List not be shared with non-members unless the explicit permission of the poster is sought and received, but AnitaB.org is not responsible for any undesired dissemination of information by members of the Systers List. You can unsubscribe from the Systers List at any time by entering your email address at the bottom of the [Systers.org](http://www.systers.org/mailman/listinfo/systers#subscribers) site and clicking “Unsubscribe or edit options.”

## **Non-identifiable Aggregated Data**

Non-identifiable data is information that subsequently is used in aggregate form or in a manner that does not readily identify an individual. We may collect non-identifiable data whether or not you are a registered member of AnitaB.org. We may use non-identifiable data for purposes of research or analysis. We may conduct research on our customer demographics, internet usage, and interests and behavior based on personal data we gather. Although non-identifiable data may be based in part on personal information, it does not identify you personally.

AnitaB.org may share this type of non-identifiable data with a variety of third parties, including its affiliates, advertisers and other current and prospective business partners. AnitaB.org may use non-identifiable data collected for website administration, advertising and promotional purposes, for understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Site(s), and we may share such information with various affiliated and unaffiliated entities for such purposes. We may also enter into agreements with outside companies that possess technology that allows us to customize our advertising and marketing messages. Your non-personally identifiable information and click stream data about your activities may be shared with these companies so this customization can be accomplished. Our agreement with these companies prohibits them from sharing your information with any third party or using it for any other purpose. Non-identifiable click stream and demographic information may also be shared with our advertisers and business partners.

## **Choice**

You may, of course, decline to share your personal information with AnitaB.org, in which case AnitaB.org will not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality found on the Site(s). If you would like us to limit communications to you or use or disclosure of your personal information, please make your request by email to [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org). We will respond within a reasonable period to notify you either that we will use reasonable efforts to accommodate your request or alternatively, that we are unable to do so and will delete your personal information from our databases. You may request a copy of any information we have about you, update your information, or request any information about to be deleted from our databases at any time by emailing [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org).

## **Access**

The accuracy of information provided by you is your responsibility. You agree you will not knowingly provide us inaccurate information. If someone has spoofed your e-mail address or you have another reason you would like to have such information edited or removed, please send an email to [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org) with your request. Other personal information may be corrected, amended or deleted by requesting changes by email to [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org).

## **Security Notice**

While AnitaB.org uses certain measures intended to improve security, it is possible that information you provide us could be intercepted or otherwise accessed by unauthorized parties. In addition, any information sent to us by email may not be secure during transit, due to the nature of email. AnitaB.org does not provide any guarantees that information will not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If AnitaB.org learns of a security breach we will immediately notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps and inform you of what we are doing to help remedy the situation.

## **International Transfers**

The Site(s) are hosted in the United States. If you choose to use the Site(s) from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personal information outside of those regions to the United States and by providing your personal information on the Site(s) you consent to that transfer. AnitaB.org will comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy regardless of where the information originates.

## **In the Event of Merger or Sale**

In the event that AnitaB.org is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

## **Third-Party Advertisers, Links to Other Sites**

The Site(s) may be linked to internet websites operated by other companies or third-party sponsors. Some of these websites may be co-branded with our name or logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us. AnitaB.org may also permit other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Site(s). These third-party ad servers or ad networks may use technology to send, directly to your browser, some of the advertisements and links that appear on the Site(s). These advertisers may automatically receive your IP address if this happens.

AnitaB.org may work with third parties (e.g., Twitter, LinkedIn, and Facebook) who use web beacons, pixel tags, JavaScript code, and other technologies to collect or receive information from our Site and elsewhere on the Internet and use that information to provide measurement and conversion services and target advertisements. You may be able to opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting by visiting [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices?__hstc=155023335.9b2f00157800b53c8fc888a234b96999.1474570080171.1474570080171.1474570080173.2&__hssc=155023335.2.1474570080173&__hsfp=1766097770) or by enabling do-not-track settings in your browser if your browser provides those settings.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party websites and third party ad servers or ad networks. AnitaB.org’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other third party advertisers or websites. Please be aware that AnitaB.org does not warn you when you have chosen to link through to another website from the Site(s).

## **Children**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, the Sites are not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 13 and AnitaB.org does not knowingly collect or maintain personal information on the Sites from persons under 13 years-of-age. Any person who provides their information to AnitaB.org through any part of Site(s) represents to AnitaB.org that they are 13 years of age or older. If AnitaB.org learns that personal information of persons less than 13 years-of-age has been collected on AnitaB.org without verifiable parental consent, then AnitaB.org will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to AnitaB.org, then you may alert AnitaB.org at [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org) and request that AnitaB.org delete that child’s personal information from its systems.

## **Cookies, Web Pixels, and Similar Technologies**

To the extent website usage information is developed through use of session cookies, we will only use this information to facilitate your use of our Site(s). Cookies are data files that are written onto your computer by a website. Cookies remember information about your activities on a website. The data collected by the cookies is associated with your computer IP address for the duration of the cookie. AnitaB.org may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. Please review your web browser “Help” file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. However, without cookies you may not have access to certain services on the Site. Third party advertisements displayed in connection with the Site may also contain cookies set by internet advertisers. We do not control these cookies and users of the Site should check the privacy policy of the advertisers to see whether and how it uses cookies.

AnitaB.org may use cookies to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) provide customized third-party advertisements, content, and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of third-party marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.

We may also automatically record certain information from your device by using various types of technology, including web beacons, pixel tags, JavaScript code, and other technologies. This automatically collected information may include your IP address or other device address or ID, web browser and/or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after you use the Site(s), the pages or other content you view or otherwise interact with on the Site(s), and the dates and times that you visit, access, or use the Site(s). We also may use these technologies to collect information regarding your interaction with email messages, such as whether you opened, clicked on, or forwarded a message. This information is gathered from all users, and may be connected with other information about you.

## **Contacting AnitaB.org**

If you would like to contact AnitaB.org regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [Privacy@AnitaB.org](mailto:privacy@anitab.org) or by postal mail at Privacy Director, Anita Borg Institute for Women and Technology, 1501 Page Mill Road, MS 1105, Palo Alto, CA 94304.
